Preliminary Inventory of the Charles Anderson Gauld Papers, 1932-1968
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles Anderson Gauld Papers,
1932-1968
44003
Gauld, Charles Anderson, 1911-
18 manuscript boxes (7.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Clippings, correspondence, pamphlets, and serial issues, relating to political, social, and economic conditions in Latin America, especially Brazil, to Latin America's role in World War II, to the Castro regime in Cuba, and to problems of birth control, food production, communism, and religion in Latin America.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Birth control--Latin America.; Communism.; Communism--Latin America.; Food supply--Latin America.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Latin America.; Brazil.; Brazil--Economic conditions.; Brazil--Politics and government.; Brazil--Social conditions.; Cuba.; Cuba--History--1959-; Cuba--Politics and government--1959-; Latin America.; Latin America--Economic conditions.; Latin America--Politics and government.; Latin America--Religion.; Latin America--Social conditions.
Container List
- Form letter from "Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors," 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Reprint of article by Richard T. Baldwin entitled "Michigan Editors Hear Hoover Tell Story of How U.S. has met World Crisis," 1932 September 30 (Folder 2)
- Page from Commonwealth regarding Dr. John Earl Baker, 1957 August 5 (Folder 3)
- Several photographs and newspaper clippings concerning the Osage Indian agency (Folder 4)
- Brochure of the 21st Annual Meeting of the George Putnam Fund of Boston (Folder 5)
- An article by C.A. Gauld concerning Herbert Hoover in Brazil, 1946 June 14 (Folder 6)
- Newspaper clippings concerning the Hoover Institution and the political career of Herbert Hoover (Folder 7)
- Newspaper clippings, leaflets, pamphlets, and other printed materials dealing with world population crises, peace movements, activities of the American Civil Liberties Union, the American Friends Service Committee, and various political matters (e.g. the USSR and Cuba, Communist China, Vietnam, Franco Spain, etc.), 1965-1968 (Folder 8)
- Memoranda written by C. A. Gauld in Washington, D.C., on American entry into World War II, 1941 December 8, 13, 20 (Folder 9)
- Political reports, broadcast summaries, handwritten notes, bulletins, memoranda, clippings and miscellaneous printed materials, gathered primarily in Washington, D.C. by C. A. Gauld, pertaining to Latin America during World War II. Much of the material is from the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (Folder 10)
- Political reports, broadcast summaries, handwritten notes, bulletins, memoranda, clippings and miscellaneous printed materials, gathered primarily in Washington, D.C. by C.A. Gauld, pertaining to Latin America during World War II. Much of the material is from the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Clippings and miscellaneous items pertaining to World War II, as well as materials on Latin America in the 1940's and Japan in the 1950's (Folder 2)
- Clippings and miscellaneous items pertaining to World War II, as well as materials on Latin America in the 1940's and Japan in the 1950's (Box 3-4)
- Booklet entitled Japan's Recovery, published by the Natural Resources Section, General Headquarters, Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers, 1950 November 15 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Typewritten reports entitled "Daily Analysis Concerning Latin America," 1942-1944 (Folder 2)
- CIAA (Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs) Analysis of Radio Propaganda - "Daily Bulletin," 1942-1944 (Folder 3)
- Latin American newspaper clippings and other miscellaneous materials pertaining to World War II (Folder 4)
- Latin American newspaper clippings and other miscellaneous materials pertaining to World War II (Box 6-9)
- Miscellaneous newspaper and magazine clippings and other printed materials pertaining to World War II (Box 9-12)